Tom Eagle BEng GradEI

Key information

- 1st class degree Mechanical Engineering BEng
- Currently studying part time MSc in renewable energy
- Highly IT literate: trained in WindFarmer by DNV GL; MS Office; C and HTML; also experience of AutoCAD, SketchUp and GIS
- High level of numeracy and literacy
- Experience of managing projects up to the value of £100k
- Tendering skills through providing quotes for customers of property business
- Building energy performance assessment using Parity Project's Home Energy Masterplan
- Feasibility assessment of renewable energy projects
- Practical aptitude with mechanical and electrical systems. Attained certification to BS7671 for electrical installations. Many years' experience of installing electrical and mechanical systems and measures to improve building performance

Personal Profile

Mature Mechanical Engineering Graduate with 9 years' experience of project management in own property services business and latterly for a green building company, consistently providing excellent customer service, delivering projects on time and on budget.

Passionate about renewable energy and sustainability issues. Currently working for a sustainable building company as a site manager while studying on an MSc course in renewable energy.

Possesses advanced problem-solving and fault finding skills, allied to sound practical judgement and has a track record of effectively working in the field. Has an affinity with IT and other technology and excellent numeracy and literacy, enabling effective and efficient record keeping and administration.

Qualifications

- (ongoing) Renewable Energy and the Built Environment MSc at CAT, Machynlleth.
 Covering building physics, wind, hydro, solar PV and thermal and other technologies.
 Wind farm constraint mapping, using WindFarmer, knowledge of feasibility studies, environment impact assessment and energy generation forecasting
- 1st class honours Mechanical Engineering UMIST (2000)
- A levels Maths (A), Physics (A), Gen Studies (A), Geography (C) 1997

Tom Eagle BEng GradEl

Employment History

Site manager, EcoVert Solutions July 2014 to present

In July my role was expanded to involve managing construction sites in addition to the existing responsibilities, to include training staff, liaising with clients, suppliers and subcontractors.

Project Assistant, EcoVert Solutions Oct 2012 to July 2014

My role is to assist in planning and execution to ensure projects are finished to a high standard, on time and on budget

EcoVert provides low energy refurbishments and new build services for commercial and domestic buildings up to PassivHaus standard.

National Trust Environment Volunteer - March 2012 – March 2013

I worked with the environmental practice advisers in Wales. Projects Included: assessing the NT's holiday properties for energy efficiency, and creating a solar and human-powered mobile generator for the trust to promote their environmental work.

Owner/Manager, Eagle Property Services – Chester April 2005 – October 2012
Responsible for managing and carrying out property maintenance/development contracts, ranging from minor repairs and mechanical/electrical installations to full property refurbishment.

Accomplishments

Eagle Property Services

- Set up own property maintenance company and managed contracts for property renovations valued up to £55,000. Maintained business through difficult period in the construction industry.
- Sourced, planned and coordinated groups of tradespeople to fully meet the project criteria.
- Learned and used MS FrontPage software to create a website to promote property company.
- Achieved certification under BS7671: requirements for electrical installations (16th edition).

Teaching/tutoring

- Coached several secondary school pupils to successful GCSE and A level results.
- Taught GCSE science to secondary school pupils as part of PGCE course.

University

- Achieved first class honours degree in Mechanical Engineering from one of UK's top institutions
- Award for outstanding results in fluid mechanics and thermodynamics at University (> 90% pass rate).

Tom Eagle BEng GradEI

- Used word processing and spreadsheet software packages to produce many technical reports to a high standard.
- Learned programming language from scratch to develop material testing equipment for university dissertation.